Guide to The Records of the American and Foreign Christian Union MC.20
New York University Archives
- Series II: General Correspondence and Mission Reports
  - J - Miscellaneous, 1866-1873 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - James, Horace (District Secretary), 1871 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Johnson, J. Gibson, 1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Jones, C. P., 1868-1869 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - K - Miscellaneous, 1865-1883 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Kalopothakes, M. D. (Missionary: Greece), 1866-1873, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Kendall, H., 1868, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Kirk, Edward N. (Vice President), 1868, 1873 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Koenig, R. (Agent: Hungary), 1867-1873 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Kramer, Henry, 1877-1878 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - L - Miscellaneous, 1866-1883 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Ladd, Henry M., 1883 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Lyman, J. H., 1866, 1868, 1872 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Mc - Miscellaneous, 1865-1879 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - M~aren, William H. (District Secretary), 1868-1873 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - MCCorkle, William A., 1869 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - McDougal, John R., 1872-1883 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - McKim, A. J. (Missionary: Peru), 1866-1868 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - McNamara, Arthur (Missionary: New York City), 1878-1879 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - M - Miscellaneous, 1866-1882 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Maas, A. (Missionary: Indianapolis), 1874-1875 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - MaCall Mission (Paris), 1882-1883 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Massarde, Philippe, 1867 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Mattison, A., 1868 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Merwin, A. M. (Missionary: Chile), 1867-1873 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Miller, August (Missionary: Chicago), 1874-1884 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Mission Evangelique de Marseille et de Nice, 1882-1883 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Mission Inteneure Evangelique, 1882-1883, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Missionaries of the AFCU, List of, 1866 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Montsalvatge, Ramon (Missionary: Columbia), 1866-1868 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Moorehead, William G. (Missionary: Italy), 1866-1879 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - N - Miscellaneous, 1866-1880 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Neuchatel Committee, 1868-1884 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Newell, Jr., WilliamW. (Board of Directors), 1879-1883 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 0 - Miscellaneous, 1868-1879 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Oeurve Evangelique de Toulon, 1882 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - P - Miscellaneous, 1866-1883 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Page, Henry F., 1872-1879 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Palmer, Levin T. and Charles J., 1873, 1880 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Park, A. Jackson(Missionary: Mexico), 1867-1872 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Pethrick, John, 1870-1873 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Phillips, S. P., 1868 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Poole, H. Ward, 1871 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Prevost, J. M. (Missionary: Mexico), 1871-1872 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Prime, Samuel Irenaus (Board of Directors), 1868-1880 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Property on 87th Street: Map and Description, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Protestant Journals and Periodicals, 1861-1871,1880 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Purlier, Lavinia (Missionary: Cincinnati), 1866-1873 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Purlier, Lavinia, 1874-1877 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Purlier, Lavinia, 1878-1884 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Q - Miscellaneous, 1877 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - R - Miscellaneous, 1866-1883 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Rankin, Melinda (Missionary: Mexico), 1866-1873 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Rankin, Melinda, 1870 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Rankin, Melinda, 1871 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Reformed Dutch Church, 1867-1868, 1883 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Report of the Meeting held at the Tabernacle Church, 1882 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Richards, George S., 1866-1867 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Riley, H. Chauncey (Missionary: Mexico), 1866-1870 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Riley, H. Chauncey (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Riley, T. W., 1871-1873 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Robinson, Charles S. (Minister, American Chapel in Parisand Board of Directors), 1871-1872 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Romero Report, 1868-1872 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Rossiter, W. D. (District Secretary), 1871 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Ruliffson, A. G., 1865-1878 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - S - Miscellaneous, 1871 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Sadd, J. M. (Missionary: Louisville),Sadd', J. M. (Missionary: Louisville), 1866-1883 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Sadd, Mrs. J. M. (Missionary: Louisville), 1866-1872 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Sadd, Mrs. J. M., 1872-1875 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Sakellarios, Demetrios L. (Missionary: Greece), 1876-1882 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Sayre, S. (Missionary: Mexico), 1865-1870 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Schenck, A. V. E., 1868-1873 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Schiller, Anna (Missionary: Cincinnati), 1871-1872 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Schiller, Anna, 1866-1876 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Scottish Reformation Society, 1877-1884 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Scovel, S. F., 1869 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Scudder, Joseph (Corresponding Secretary) and Anna Scudder, 1871-1872 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Smith, D. W., 1868-1877 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Smith, T. Ralston (Board of Directors), 1878-1880 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Societe Central Protestante D'Evangelisation, 1866-1870, 1875 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Societe Evangelique de Belge, 1880, 1882-1883 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Societe Evangelique de France, 1863-1882 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Societe Evangelique de Geneve, 1878-1883 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Southern Presbyterian Church, 1880, 1883 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Spanish Mission, 1868-1869, 1883 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Stebbins, James H., 1871-1872 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Stevenson, F. P., 1870, 1873, 1877 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Stewart, William B., 1866-1876, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - T - Miscellaneous, 1866-1883 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Taylor, R. (District Secretary), 1866-1875 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Thompson, John B., 1865, 1868, 1872 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Thompson, J~ T., 1867-1868 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Thouronot, E., 1882 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Trumbull, David (Missionary: Chile), 1867-1880 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Tugwell, L. S., 1870 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Turner, Robert, 1871 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - U - Miscellaneous, 1868 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified Authors, 1863, 1868 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - United States Christian Commission, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - United States Supreme Court: AFCU v. Matilda Yount, 1877 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - V - Miscellaneous, 1866-1882 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Van Nest, A. R., Jr. (Missionary: Italy), 1865-1873 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Vermilye, Jacob D. (President), 1872-1880 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Verrue, E. (Missionary: San Francisco), 1882-1883 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - W - Miscellaneous, 1863-1882 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Walch, Patrick, 1872, 1877 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Waldenses: Chiesa Evangelica Valdese, 1876-1883 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Waldenses: French, 1882 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Waldenses: Report of the Waldensian Normal School, 1879 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Waldensian Table, 1878-1880 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Waldensian Theological College, 1868 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Welch, Michel (District Secretary), 1865-1870 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - West, E. Spencer (Board of Directors), 1867-1870 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Westrup, Alfred B., 1868 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - White, J. G., 1870-1875, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Wier, A. W. (Missionary: Davenport), 1874-1875 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Willard, S. and Jane, 1872, 1:875, 1880 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Wolcott, Frederick H. (Board of Directors), 1870, 1875-1883 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Wood, F. W., 1878 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Wood, John, 1870, 1873 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Woods, Henry, 1868 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Woodcuff, A., 1866-1871, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Wright, Julia McNair, 1871-1872 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Y - Miscellaneous, 1878, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Yaunch, J. (Missionary: Cleveland), undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Young, T. S. (Treasurer), 1865-1882 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Young Men's Christian Association, 1866, 1868 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - z - Miscellaneous, 1866 (Box 12, Folder 28)
- Series III: Financial Records
  This series contains Treasurer's Reports (1871-1883), Checks (1882-1884), Letters of Receipt (1882-1884), and miscellaneous records (1856-1871). Each type of record is arranged in chronological order.
  - Daniel Fanshaw, Printer and Publisher, Account, 1856-1857 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Vernon Brothers Bills, 1857-1858 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Stuyvesant Bank Book, 1868-1869 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Report of the Special Committee on the Financial Condition of the AFCU, 1871 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1871-1872 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1873-1874 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1874-1875 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1875-1876 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1876-1877 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1877-1878 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1880-1881 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1881-1882 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1882-1883 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Checks (Pacific Bank), 1882-1883 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Checks (Pacific Bank), 1883-1884 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Letters of Receipt, 1882 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Letters of Receipt, 1883 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Receipt, 1883 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Receipt, 1883 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Letters of Receipt, 1833 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Letters of Receipt, 1884 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Series IV: The Christian World
  This series is composed of letters of subscription to The Christian World, arranged chronologically. The letters often contain additional comment and information.
  - Letters of Subscription, 1877 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1878 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1878 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1878 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1878 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1879 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1879 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1879 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1879 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1880 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1880 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1880 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1881 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1881 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1882 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1882 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1883 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1883 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Letters of Subscription, 1884 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Series V: Commission of the American Fund for the Evangelicalization of France
  This series contains correspondence documenting the initiation, work, and effect of the Commission which sponsored a deputation of French evangelicals on a fund-raising tour of the United States. The papers are arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1880 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1880 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1880 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1881 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Series VI: Reorganization
  This series is composed of all AFCU records from April of 1884, when the Union was reorganized to solely promote and pursue efforts toward the evangelization of France, until the Union ceased its active work altogether in November of 1884. During this period, George B. Safford acted as corresponding secretary and treasurer and was also responsible for the promotion of the Union among the various ecclesiastical bodies. The papers in this series have been grouped as Correspondence and Financial Records and are arranged chronologically. Some correspondence addresses the impact of the reorganization upon the success of the Union's work.
  - Correspondence, 1884 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1884 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1884 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Financial Records: Letters of Receipt, 1884 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Financial Records:Checks, 1884 (Box 18, Folder 9)